Oh, damn. They cancelled my Visa.
Bon sang, ma Visa est bloquée.
Oh, yay, a new MasterCard.
Génial, ma nouvelle MasterCard.
-What? -I was going to get my mail.
- Quoi ? - J'allais chercher mon courrier.
Okay.
Ok.
Are you hoping to get it telepathically?
Tu essaies de le faire venir par télépathie ?
I think you mean telekinetically.
Par télékinésie, tu veux dire.
Wasn't sure of the protocol now you and Leonard are no longer having coitus.
J'étais pas sûr du protocole depuis que Leonard et toi ne copulez plus.
God, can we please just say "no longer seeing each other"?
Tu veux bien dire ”ne vous voyez plus" ?
Well, we could if it were true.
Si c'était vrai, oui.
You live in the same building. You see each other all the time.
Vous Vivez dans le même immeuble, vous vous voyez.
The variable which has changed is the coitus.
La variable qui a changé, c‘est la copulation.
Okay, here's the protocol.
Ok, voilà le protocole.
You and l are still friends, and you stop saying coitus.
On reste amis, toi et moi, si tu arrêtes de dire "copuler".
Good. I'm glad we're still friends.
Je suis content qu‘on soit encore amis.
-Really? -Oh, yes.
- Vraiment ? - Oui.
It was a lot of work to accommodate you in my life.
C'était du boulot de t'adapter à ma vie.
I'd hate for that effort to have been in vain.
J'aurais pas voulu que ces efforts s‘avèrent vains.
Right.
D‘accord.
Just to be clear...
J'ai le droit de dire ”copuler" si c‘est pas à toi que je parie ?
Everyone.
Non, à personne.
Harsh terms, but all right.
Tu négocies dur. Ok.
-l'll just substitute "intercourse." -Great.
- Je vais utiliser "rapport." -Extra.
SHELDON: Or "fornication." Yeah--
Ou "fornication."
But that has judgmental overtones, so I'll hold that in reserve.
Mais ça un côté jugement, je le garde en réserve.
So how you been?
Alors, comment ça a été ?
Well, my existence is a continuum...
Mon existence est un continuum
...so I've been what I am at each point in the implied time period.
donc j'ai été ce que je suis à chaque point de la période passée.
You're just coitusing with me, aren't you?
Tu te fous de moi, pas vrai ?
-How's Leonard doing? -He seems all right...
- Comment va Leonard ? - Ça a l‘air d'aller.
...although he does spend a disturbing amount of time...
Mais il passe un temps inquiétant
...looking at photographs of you and smelling the pillow you slept on.
à regarder des photos de toi et à humer ton oreiller.
Although now that I think of it, he asked me not to tell you that.
Maintenant que j'y pense, il m‘a demandé de ne pas te dire ça.
PENNY: I'll pretend I didn't hear it.
Je ferai comme si je n‘avais rien entendu.
I'd rather you pretend I didn't say it.
Fais plutôt comme si je n‘avais rien dit.
I see you bought Mama ltalia marinara spaghetti sauce.
Tu as acheté dela sauce marinara pour spaghetti Mama Italia.
-Yep. -That's the sauce my mother uses.
- Oui. - Ma mère l'utilise.
She likes cooking Italian...
Elle aime cuisiner italien
...because, according to her, that's what the Romans made Jesus eat.
parce qu'elle croit que les Romains nourrissaient Jésus comme ça.
Interesting. I'll have to have you over for spaghetti some night.
Intéressant. Viens manger des spaghetti, un soir.
I'm hungry now.
J'ai faim maintenant.
Will you cut up hot dogs into little chunks and mix them in with the sauce?
Tu vas mettre des dés de saucisse dans la sauce ?
-I don't have hot dogs. -lt's all right. I do.
- J'ai pas de saucisses. - Pas grave, j'en ai.
-Hey, where you been? -I was talking with Penny.
- D'où tu Viens ? - Je parlais à Penny.
What's wrong with you? You can't hang out with your roommate's ex.
T'es àla masse, tu peux pas trainer avec l'ex de ton coloc.
That's totally uncool.
C‘est pas cool.
No, it's fine. I don't care. I'm over it.
Je m'en fiche, j'ai tourné la page.
Yeah. That's why he's been whining...
C‘est pour ça qu'il geint
...about trying to invent that memory-wiper gizmo from Men in Black.
et veut inventer le truc de Men in Black qui rend amnésique.
Is he making any progress?
Il avance ?
Because I'd like to erase Ben Affleck as Daredevil.
J'aimerais oublier Ben Affleck dans Daredevil.
So would Ben Affleck.
Ben Affleck aussi.
The point is, in a situation like this, you gotta pick sides.
Dans ce genre de cas, il faut choisir son camp.
You're either on team Leonard or team Penny.
Tu es soit dans l'équipe Leonard ou Penny.
-Which one picks last? -What?
- Qui choisit en dernier ? - Quoi ?
Usually, I'm on the team that picks last.
Je suis toujours choisi en dernier.
Unless there's a kid in a wheelchair.
Sauf s'il y a un gosse en fauteuil.
Sheldon, I got you your tangerine chicken.
Sheldon, j'ai ton poulet à la mandarine.
I hope you're hungry.
J'espère que tu as faim.
Well, of course I'm hungry.
Bien sûr que j'ai faim.
And as l have no plans to eat with any other team...
Je ne prévois pas de manger avec une autre équipe
...I will consume my tangerine chicken with the appropriate gusto.
etje vais donc consommer mon poulet avec appétit.
Okay.
Ok.
Just out of curiosity, do we still have hot dogs?
Par curiosité, il nous reste des saucisses ?
I don't know. Why?
Je sais pas. Pourquoi ?
Just making dinner conversation.
Je fais juste la conversation.
Go team Leonard.
Vive l'équipe Leonard.
-Oh, God, this is good. -Let me ask you a question.
- C‘est délicieux. - J'ai une question.
Do you believe you're going to go to hell for eating sweet-and-sour pork?
Tu crois que tu iras en enfer pour avoir mangé du porc aigre douce ?
Jews don't have hell. We have acid reflux.
Les Juifs ne connaissent pas l'enfer. Juste les remontées acides.
Do you want the last dumpling, Sheldon?
Tu veux le dernier, Sheldon ?
Certainly. It's not like I have to moderate my food intake...
Certes. C‘est pas comme si je devais manger modérément
...because I'm planning on eating again very shortly.
parce que je vais refaire un repas bientôt.
So you wanna do something tonight?
On fait quoi ce soir ?
No, I can't. I gotta pick up my mom from her water-aerobics class.
Je dois aller chercher ma mère à son cours d'aquagym.
Eighteen overweight women flapping their arm fat...
18 femmes en surpoids agitant leurs bras graisseux
...in a swimming pool.
dans une piscine.
It's like the manatee tank at SeaWorld.
On croirait le bassin des lamantins à SeaWorld.
-What about you, Raj? -Oh, there it is.
- Et toi, Raj ? - Et voilà.
Now you don't have a girlfriend you wanna hang out with me again.
T'as plus de copine, alors tu veux à nouveau me voir.
I never stopped hanging out with you.
J'ai jamais arrêté de te voir.
I'm the friend you call when you have no other options.
Je ne suis qu'un bouche—trou.
If we were the Justice League, I'd be Aquaman.
Si on était la Ligue des Justiciers, je serais Aquaman.
lwish you were Aquaman.
J'aimerais que tu sois Aquaman.
Then I could send you to scoop my mom out of the old-lady tank.
Je t‘enverrais choper ma mère dans le bassin aux Vieilles.
Excuse me, I'm thirsty...
Pardon, j'ai soif.
...so I'm going to go to the refrigerator and get myself a refreshing beverage.
Je vais donc chercher une boisson fraiche dans le frigo.
You know what? I'll just spend the evening alone.
Je vais passer la soirée tout seul.
What? Suddenly, I'm not good enough for you?
Quoi ? Je suis pas assez bien pour toi, c‘est ça ?
I do so love beverages.
J'aime les boissons.
Now I think I'll take my after-dinner walk.
Je vais aller faire ma balade digestive.
Since when do you take after-dinner walks?
Depuis quand tu fais des balades digestives ?
Since when do you take walks?
Depuis quand tu fais des balades ?
I read a study online that walking after a meal not only aids in digestion...
J'ai lu sur le net qu‘une marche aprés le repas aide la digestion
...but increases serotonin.
et augmente le taux de sérotonine.
If there's one thing I like more than a refreshing beverage, it's serotonin. Bye.
Sii y a une chose que je préfére aux boissons, c‘est la sérotonine.
-Hold on. I'll walk down with you. -Oh, that's not necessary.
Attends, je Viens avec toi.
You can go first.
Vas—y en premier.
Or we could go together.
On pourrait y aller ensemble.
I can't think of a reason why not.
Je ne vois aucune raison de dire non.
-Let's go. -Hold on.
- Allons-y. - Attends.
Nope. No reason.
Non, aucune raison.
I've missed you.
Tu m'as manqué.
All right, say hello to your mother for me.
Bon, salue ta mère de ma part.
Okay.
Ok.
What?
Quoi ?
You said you were going for a walk.
Tu as dit que tu allais te balader.
I didn't say outside.
J'ai pas dit dehors.
So what, you're gonna walk up and down the stairs?
Tu vas monter et descendre les escaliers ?
No, of course not.
Bien sûr que non.
That would be odd and suspicious behavior.
Ce serait aussi étrange que suspicieux.
-Here, Rumples. Here, boy. -Which way are you going?
- Au pied, Rumples. - Tu pars par où ?
-I parked my scooter down the block.
- J'ai garé scooter en bas dela rue.
I'm going the other way. Bye.
Je vais dans l‘autre sens. Salut.
Bye.
Salut.
Oh, actually, I'm this way.
En fait, c‘est par la.
Do I smell hot dogs?
Ça sent la saucisse ?
No. I mean, I have no idea what you smell.
Non. Je veux dire, je sais pas ce que ça sent.
Well, I definitely smell raw hot dog.
J'ai senti de la saucisse crue.
Perhaps you're getting a brain tumor.
Tu as peut-être une tumeur au cerveau.
All right, have a nice walk.
Allez, bonne balade.
I shall. Have a nice scoot.
Bon scooter.
You might wanna stand back. I'm sitting on top of 13 horses here.
Recule, je chevauche un 13 chevaux.
Oh, hello, doggie. Nice doggie.
Salut, le chien. Gentil toutou.
I bet you think you smell hot dogs.
Tu sens la saucisse, je parie.
Look, a cat.
Regarde, un chat.
SHELDON: Penny.
Penny.
Here.
Tiens.
I had to trade the others for my life.
J'ai échangé les autres contre ma vie.
-Hey, Leonard? -Yeah?
- Leonard ? -Oui ?
I haven't had sex in a year.
J'ai pas couché depuis un an.
Where are you going with this, Raj?
Où tu veux en venir, Raj ?
Don't flatter yourself, dude.
Te flatte pas trop.
-I wanna go out and meet a woman. -So go.
- Je veux sortir voir des filles. - Va.
I need a wingman. I don't wanna come off like a lonely loser.
Il me faut un assistant. Je veux pas passer pour un loser esseulé.
And you think my presence will help with that?
Ma présence t‘y aiderait ?
Well, I do. Next to you, I look like a catch.
Oui. A côté de toi, j'ai l‘air d'un super parti.
-l'm not going out tonight, Raj. -All right.
- Je sors pas ce soir. - D‘accord.
Would you mind if I went to your room and downloaded Asian pornography?
Ça t'embête si je télécharge du porno asiatique dans ta chambre ?
Very much.
Beaucoup.
Doesn't have to be Asian.
Pas forcément asiatique.
-Don't worry. You'll meet a girl. -No, I won't.
- Tu rencontreras quelqu‘un. - Non.
Yes, you will. And she'll be beautiful...
Si. Elle sera belle,
...and kind and sexy and funny and everything you ever wanted in a woman.
et gentille, sexy, drôle. Elle aura ce que tu veux chez une femme.
-You really think so? -I do.
- Tu crois vraiment ? - Oui.
You'll fall hopelessly in love and give her your heart.
Tu tomberas éperdument amoureux, lui donneras ton coeur.
She'll take it and grind it into pathetic little pieces.
Elle le piétinera et le réduira en de pathétiques miettes.
We will have sex first, right?
Mais avant, on couchera ?
That's Italian.
C‘est italien.
So was Leonard okay with you coming over?
Leonard a bien pris ta venue ici ?
In fact, he said, "I'm fine. I don't care."
Il a dit : "ça va, je m'en fiche."
In no manner which would lead one to believe...
Et pas d‘une façon qui laisserait penser
...that he was covering up feelings of anguish and betrayal.
qu'il masquait sa souffrance et son sentiment de trahison.
-Well, good. -l'm also pleased to report...
- Tant mieux. - J'ai la joie d‘ajouter
...that he's all cried out over you.
qu'il ne pleure plus à cause de toi.
He's been crying?
Il a pleuré ?
Oh, I believe that was something else I wasn't supposed to mention.
Encore un détail que je ne devais pas révéler.
Oh, God. I feel terrible.
Je me sens très mal.
Do you have a stomachache too?
Toi aussi tu as mal à l‘estomac ?
No. Why, do you?
Non, pourquoi ? Toi oui ?
Why did you ask if I had one too?
Pourquoi tu me demandes ça ?
Just making polite dinner conversation.
Je fais la conversation, par politesse.
Yourturn.
A ton tour.
All right.
D‘accord.
So, what's new in your life?
Quoi de neuf dans ta vie ?
Well, my new shoes are not made for running.
Mes nouvelles chaussures ne sont pas faites pour la course.
Have you been running?
Tu cours ?
It's just a suspicion l have.
Mais je le sens.
-l'm so glad you like it. -I do.
- Ravie que ça te plaise. - Ça me plait.
Leonard never cooks for me.
Leonard ne cuisine jamais pour moi.
Well, maybe that's because Leonard can't cook.
Sans doute parce qu'il ne sait pas cuisiner.
You can't cook and you made me this.
Toi non plus, tu as quand même fait ça.
Whatever. Oh, let me get the cheesecake out of the fridge.
Bref. Je vais sortir le gâteau au fromage du frigo.
Oh, Lord, I'm in Jewish hell.
Je suis dans l‘enfer des Juifs.
Look at this. Do you think she's really doing that or is it Photoshop?
Regarde. Elle le fait vraiment ou c‘est du Photoshop ?
I'm sure Martha Stewart never got naked...
Martha Stewart ne s‘estjamais mise nue
...with a room full of big fat Japanese guys.
dans une pièce pleine de japonais obèses.
You don't know that.
Tu n'en sais rien.
Prison changes people.
La prison, ça vous change une femme.
Hey, where you been?
Où tu étais ?
I told you. Walking.
Je me baladais.
For an hour and a half?
Pendant une heure et demie ?
I got lost.
Je me suis perdu.
How could you get lost? Your phone has GPS.
Comment ? Tu as un GPS sur ton téléphone.
Satellites are down. Solar flares.
Les satellites sont en pannes, à cause des éruptions solaires.
-There are no solar flares now. SHELDON: Yes, there are.
- Il n‘y en a pas en ce moment. - Si.
Dude, I'm an astrophysicist. If there were solar flares, I'd be all up in it.
Je suis astrophysicien. S'il y en avait, j‘y serais à fond.
I'm sorry, I misspoke.
Je me suis mal exprimé.
What I meant to say was my battery died.
Je voulais dire: je n‘avais plus de batterie.
-What the hell was that about? -I don't know.
- C‘était quoi, ça ? - Aucune idée.
Do you think this is really Hillary Clinton doing it with Oprah?
C‘est vraiment Hillary Clinton s'envoyant Oprah ?
Aw, we really need to get you a girl.
Il te faut vraiment une copine.
SHELDON: Leonard.
Leonard.
-Leonard. -Oh,just come in!
- Leonard. - Entre !
Thanks for seeing me on such short notice.
Merci de me recevoir à l‘improviste.
What do you want, Sheldon?
Qu‘est—ce que tu veux ?
Maybe this isn't a good time.
Je tombe mai.
Tell me why you woke me up or I swear to God I will kill you.
Dis—moi pourquoi tu me réveilles ou je te tue.
Do you really think death threats are an appropriate way to begin conversation?
Des menaces de mort sont—elles un bon début de discussion ?
Sometimes your lack of social skills astonishes me.
Ton manque de finesse sociale me sidère parfois.
What do you want?
Qu‘est—ce que tu veux ?
You may wanna sit down.
Tu devrais t'asseoir.
I'm in bed.
Je suis dans mon lit.
Point taken. You may wanna sit up.
Exact. Tu devrais t'asseoir dans ton lit.
Sheldon!
Sheldon !
I've been seeing Penny behind your back.
Je vois Penny dans ton dos.
Okay.
Ok.
When you say "seeing Penny," what exactly does that mean?
Qu'entends-tu par "voir" Penny ?
We had dinner last night.
On a dîné ensemble hier.
She made me spaghetti with little hot dogs cut up in it.
Elle m‘a fait des spaghetti avec des saucisses en dés.
Well, little hot dog.
Enfin, une saucisse.
I gave up the other five hot dogs to a real dog.
J'ai dû lâcher les cinq autres à un chien.
A real big dog.
Un très gros chien.
A hell hound.
Un chien de l'enfer.
It's tangential to the primary story. How about I circle back to it?
C‘est une tangente, j‘y reviendrai aprés l'histoire principale.
Fine. Why did you have dinner with Penny?
Pourquoi as-tu dîné avec Penny ?
She made spaghetti with little hot dogs.
Elle a fait des spaghetti et des saucisses.
I like spaghetti with little hot dogs.
J'aime les spaghetti avec des saucisses.
Well, then why did you have Chinese food with us?
Alors pourquoi avoir mangé chinois avec nous ?
I didn't wanna upset you.
Pour ne pas te bouleverser.
Howard made it very clear that my allegiance should be to male comrades...
Howard a été clair : je dois être fidèle à mes camarades
...before women who sell their bodies for money.
et non à des femmes vendant leur corps.
Is it possible he said, "Bros before ho's"?
A-t-il dit ”les potes avant les putes" ?
Yes, but I rephrased it to avoid offending the ho's.
Oui, j'ai reformulé pour ne pas insulter les prostituées.
Sheldon, I don't care if you wanna be friends with Penny.
Tu peux être ami avec Penny.
So the turmoil that has been keeping me...
Le tourment qui me prive
...from achieving REM sleep was entirely unjustified?
de sommeil profond est donc injustifié ?
Yes.
Oui.
Well, then as my meemaw would say...
Alors comme dirait ma mamie:
...looks like we butchered a pig, but nobody wanted bacon.
j'ai tué le cochon mais personne ne voulait de bacon.
I guess not.
On dirait bien.
And now, as promised, the tangent.
Comme promis, la tangente:
Sheldon and the Hell Hound.
Sheldon elle Chien de l‘Enfer
Or Howl Lost My Hot Dogs.
Ou Commemj'ai perdu mes saucisses.
-I can come back. -Don't be silly.
- Je peux repasser. - Sois pas bête.
We're neighbors. We're gonna run into each other. May as well get used to it.
On est voisins, autant s'habituer à se croiser.
Yeah. I guess you're right.
Tu as sûrement raison.
-Used to it yet? -Nope.
- Tu t'habitues ? - Non.
Me neither.
Moi non plus.
Oh. Sheldon seemed to think I'd be upset about you hanging out.
Sheldon pensait que je serais contre votre amitié.
But I want you to know it's fine.
Sache que c‘est pas le cas.
Oh, good. Because his mother called me.
Tant mieux, parce que sa mère m‘a appelée.
-His mother? -Yeah, she wants me...
- Sa mère ? - Elle veut
...to take him shopping for sheets and towels.
que je l'emmène acheter des draps et des serviettes.
l was gonna do that.
J'allais le faire.
Oh, well, then you do it.
Vas-y, fais—le.
I don't wanna do it. You can do it.
J'ai pas envie. Fais—le.
Okay, then you can take him for shoes.
Bon, tu l‘emmèneras acheter des chaussures.
I just took him for shoes.
Je Viens de le faire.
Well, all I know is he says they hurt his feet.
Il dit qu‘elles lui font mal aux pieds.
Fine. I'll take him for shoes next Saturday.
Bien, on ira samedi prochain.
No. A bunch of us from work are going to Disneyland next Saturday...
Non, des collègues et moi allons à Disneyland samedi,
...and Sheldon wants to come.
et Sheldon veut venir.
You're taking him to Disneyland?
Tu l'emmènes à Disneyland ?
Well, he heard me making plans on the phone. Was I gonna say no?
Il m‘a entendu en parler au téléphone, j'allais pas lui dire non.
All right, but let me know if you're gonna stuff him with junk food.
D‘accord, mais si tu le gaves de fast—food, dis-Ie moi.
I don't wanna bring home a nice dinner for him and see it go to waste.
Je ne vais pas lui ramener un bon diner si c‘est pour le gâcher.
We're going to Disneyland. He's gonna eat junk food.
On va à Disneyland, il va manger des cochonneries.
All I'm saying is give me a heads-up.
Je veux juste être prévenu.
Okay, whatever.
D‘accord, si tu veux.
And don't let him go on Space Mountain after he eats.
Ne le laisse pas faire le Space Mountain aprés un repas.
He'll say he can handle it, but you'll end up with churro puke on your shoes.
Il dira qu'il peut et tu finiras avec un churro digéré sur tes pompes.
All right. Got it. Anything else?
Compris. Autre chose ?
Don't let Goofy near him.
Ne laisse pas Dingo l'approcher.
He'll have nightmares, and I'll have to deal with it.
Il fera des cauchemars, et ce sera à moi de gérer ça.
-What's the problem with Goofy? -Wish I knew. He's fine with Pluto.
- Dingo, pourquoi ? - Aucune idée. Pluto, ça va.
Do you think the elastic woman in The Incredibles...
Tu crois que la femme élastique de The Incredibles...
...needs to use birth control or can she just be a diaphragm?
prend la pilule, ou bien utilise un diaphragme ?
Well, that's it. We're officially out of things to talk about.
C‘est officiel, on a plus de sujets de conversation.
We're home.
C‘est nous.
It's 10:00. Where have you been?
Il est 22h, vous étiez où ?
We stayed for the California Adventure water show.
On est restés voir le spectacle aquatique.
It was pure Disney magic.
De la magie Disney à l'état pur.
-l was gonna see that with him. -How was I to know that?
- Je devais y aller avec lui. - J'en savais rien.
It's all right. I'll see it again with you.
C‘est rien, j‘y retournerai avec toi.
l have food here. You were gonna call.
J'ai à manger. Tu devais téléphoner.
-I know, I know. -I can still eat.
- Je sais. - Je peux manger.
No. You already threw up once. Put on your p.j.'s and brush your teeth.
Non, tu as déjà vomi une fois. Mets ton pyjama et brosse—toi les dents.
Okay, but just don't fight.
Ok, mais ne vous disputez pas.
-We're not fighting. -Just go.
- On se dispute pas. - File.
Aren't you gonna thank Penny for taking you?
Dis merci à Penny de t‘avoir emmené.
Thank you, Penny.
Merci, Penny.
You're welcome, sweetie.
De rien, mon chou.
Want a cup of coffee?
Tu veux un café ?
Oh, I should probably get going.
Je devrais y aller.
-Come on, it's just a cup of coffee. -Yeah. Okay.
- C'estjuste un café. - D‘accord.
Yeah, the whole thing seems a little twisted to me too.
Tout ça me parait tordu, à moi aussi.
What am I smelling?
Qu‘est—ce que ça sent ?
Sheldon's churro on my shoes.
Le churro de Sheldon, sur mes pompes.
Such an angel when he's asleep.
Un vrai petit ange quand il dort.
Yeah, shame he has to wake up.
Dommage qu'il se réveille.
I think we can do it.
On peut y arriver.
Smother Sheldon in his sleep? Wouldn't that be wrong?
A étouffer Sheldon dans son sommeil ? Mais c‘est mal.
No, be friends. You and me.
Non, à être amis. Toi et moi.
Oh, sure.
Bien sûr.
Absolutely.
Absolument.
Good. I'm glad.
Bien. Je suis contente.
Here's an idea. I'm just throwing it out there. Friends who have sex.
J'ai une idée : il y a des amis qui couchent ensemble.
Good night, Leonard.
Bonne nuit, Leonard.
Kidding. Just a couple of friends goofing around.
Je plaisante. Une petite blague entre amis.
No, Goofy, no.
Non, pas Dingo.
[ENGLISH - US - SDH]
[FRENCH]